hi welcome back to ariana garcia
and here we go we're now reached the
17th chapter
which is lakitaka it's uh
it's a
investigation into the nature of karma
and the seats for karma
and
we went through and and we were saying
that this
chapter is unusual because
we can understand understand it it
doesn't even seem like the graduate
don't worry
he's gonna lose us later
and
personally i was wondering why
he went through sort of the abhidharma
presentation on
karma
dividing it into intention
and the actions of body and speech that
are intended
and then he went through some kind of
obscure
abhidharma ideas about
different kinds of karma
that you can see a person's intention or
a halo or an aura that forms around them
good or bad and then that's another kind
of karma
do you guys want anybody want to make
and guess why
he's going to obscure
abhidharma presentations of karma
because they're easy they're easy
that's
why
why is he working on that
you can just really think karma's coming
from his own side
don't forget to tell ellie okay
yeah everybody was i'll be done at that
time for 700 years and then he was
trying to reverse that tidal wave
and he did by the way single-handedly he
stood in front of a whole whole ocean
of accountants from the abu dhabi school
and he turned them all into hippies yay
uh so anyway
yeah so here he here he's going okay and
we were wondering if if you remember
why he didn't just describe the 10 good
deeds or the 10 bad bits and guess what
he does next you ready
means white karma
or good karma
lam chupa the ten paths okay so that the
ten good days the ten commandments in
buddhism are called the ten paths
of white karma
uh should do
chu dubai top these are a method of a ch
of achieving dharma and then choni llama
says
when the guardian says dharma here are
in the guardian he means
higher births
and definite good okay definite good is
called nellig
or and it and it means nirvana and
buddhahood so
when the guardian says in the first line
and a half
there are 10 paths of white karma
and you can these are a method of
achieving the dharma he means
uh higher births and and nirvana and
buddhahood
then the line just says the result of
this dharma
is this and other
anybody want to take a guess of what
this another is
uh you get good results
in this life and other lives they're
started right seen in this life and seen
in future lives
okay
and especially you're gonna get de pe
yenten uh
the good stuff of the desire room
okay nice things to eat nice nice music
to listen to soft blankets
you know just think of the the wonders
of your future life when you follow
these 10 good deeds you know how what a
cushy life you're gonna have you know
you're gonna get expensive creams for
your face
okay
and
i don't know about you but i start to i
was like
that's weird uh
it doesn't seem like it doesn't seem
like the guardian would just say you're
gonna get a new car
your hair is gonna go back
uh you're gonna get uh energy you know
and
and then we find out
from tony lama
he is
criticizing
okay got it uh he's saying oh great the
10 good deeds what more money more car
more hair
you're going to be healthy you know and
then
we find out from choni lama
this is nagarjuna
sort of
saying
look how people talk about karma you
know look how these guys talk about
karma you look at the purposes they want
to put karma to
you know and then he's criticized in
there
and what he criticizes is deeper than
you think
it's fine to get a lot of money it's
fine to get a nascar it's fine to have a
good apartment but it's not fine to
think that there's a self-existent
relationship
between doing the ten and getting that
stuff okay is it okay to have a nice
apartment yes can i be can i have a big
bank account yeah that's fine you can
help more people
uh can i have a big car yeah you can fit
more people and go to parties at john
brady's house
and they're not
okay but uh but if you think
there's a self-existent connection
between helping other people or doing
the medicine buddha mantra and getting
all these nice things if you think that
connection
doesn't come from you
then then
something's going to happen in the next
verse okay
so the next verse kind of reveals what
we're really thinking about by the way i
like this uh tony lama says
he has a side comment on that last verse
and there's the picture that he's using
with the guy with the airplane tickets
and he says by the way
this verse in general is a criticism
of people who are focusing on karma to
get stuff
not because this stuff is wrong
but because their feeling about the
connection between the karma and stuff
is too solid
they don't understand the emptiness of
that connection he said so so that's
okay
can we could also say
we could have added another line to this
verse that said you will get house
you'll get apartment you know you'll get
healthy
and you'll get enlightened
and he said if it was me i would have
added a line to the verse
uh one more line okay so just be aware
that guy with the airplane ticket and a
passport that's a passport to
enlightenment
okay which is also comes from the 10
goodies all right
then the next verse reveals nagarjuna's
opinion
about the last verse okay and here it
goes
okay
if you
if you do that kind of takpa what's
takba
b-r-t-a-g
yeah
if you do
if that's
if that's the best investigation you
could do a climber
okay
mumble you're gonna get into a big pile
of problems
many big piles of problems you know so
the guardian is like
the other guy can just see him he's like
well i just think you should do the 10
good deeds because you can get lots of
money and stuff he says
think like you do the prediction like
that
big trouble
big big so many problems gonna come from
that doing your medicine buddha mantras
because
you think you're you're gonna be healthy
later
just for that
and to think there's a connection like
that between the mantra and the good
health
you're going to get into a lot of
problems later
like what they thought
then the guardian goes further it says
your kind of prediction is an
anti-prediction
okay your investigation is a
stupa investigation
okay
you gotta that's an idiot's
investigation what
you're gonna use karma just to get some
money or or just to uh cure your your
hair or something you know
that's
by the way not wrong to get money not
wrong to get here
uh just wrong to think there's an
automatic connection
okay it's how you
think about the mantra it's not the
mantra
all right
and i have a
i have two kids here
these are twins
and you know when you when you see them
you assume it's a picture of two twins
but that's an assumption they may not be
twins at all they may just be from they
may just look similar okay
yeah you can do the mantra and something
might happen
but is there a connection between the
two
is it really what you think you see okay
all right and that takes us to the next
verse
by the way there's an
investigation
into karma
that you could have done which would
have been a better investigation not
stupid
okay you could have had a smart
investigation
which one is that
well it was described by the buddha
and by the self-made buddhists and by
the great listeners these are arhats
people are reached nirvana
if you're gonna do an investigation
into karma i suggest you follow their
investigation and not your investigation
okay not
not think there's a self-existent
connection between
medicine buddha mantra and and those you
know money and good health and okay i i
suggest you shift your investigation
to what
to the one that the buddha described
okay
all right well what's that uh didn't
interrupt the juba ja
i'm gonna tell you
okay i'm gonna tell you so perfectly
raptor means
i'm gonna set you straight
okay uh
then then he goes off on a very deep
subject and difficult subject so finally
nagarjuna took off the gloves
and he's going to show you his real
style so here he goes hang
fasten your seatbelt here we go okay
pangaji dardashian chick
okay and there's a bunch of problems in
the carvings but i figured it out
so panga
means a contract and it's often used for
loans
when you borrow money two thousand years
ago you have to sign a banja okay or
when you get married
you have to sign a bunga so it could be
a marriage contract
and it could be a loan agreement okay
he says
[Music]
and you have to read across the lines
okay you have to say chu misa
okay and you guys know chumisa i taught
you an alarm over and over and over and
over again four laws of karma
misawa
last for the fourth of the laws of karma
if you
if you do do something
you will get a result okay
literally chapel means if you do
something chimney salah means it's not
just gonna fade away over time you can't
hope
that you can lie to your mom
and then you know the conference is
gonna wear out sooner or later before
20 people lie back to you okay like you
can't
you shouldn't hope
that
you can do something wrong keep it quiet
don't tell anybody and after time
everyone's gonna forget
because that's not how karma works okay
everything's recorded and everything
expands
so
you know don't
he says
that principle misawa okay don't forget
that word because we're gonna have to
come back to it over and over again in
this part
misawa means
in tibetan
things karma's not just gonna fade away
if you wait long enough okay in fact the
opposite
okay so don't think to misawa now
he says that
now in abhidharma
you can take a general proof
and
in the abu dharm school it it becomes a
tool
the fact that chu
the fact that karma doesn't just fade
away in abu dharma system is a separate
thing
it's a real thing like a cup
or a table
hey
did you bring your cup yeah did you put
it on the table yeah how's your chimney
sound doing
you know
what
how's the fact that your karma's not
going to fade away how does that feel
this morning
and in fact in the abu dhabi system
every time you do anything you also do
it to me song
you give money you do a chimichanga
got it you do a nice thing for somebody
you pick up another chimichanga you put
it
here's another chimichanga means that
good deed is not going to just go away
so good could be for good deeds or badly
and they do that in abu dhabi they have
an idea like topa
when you achieve nirvana
what connects you to the nirvana
then
in fact there's a problem in abijah
because you're not there anymore
then you got to get a you got to get a
achieve an achievement
and it's a it's a it's an entity it's
like a cup
okay do you do you have an achievement
did you reach the running yesterday yes
did they give you an achievement
no oh my god you're gonna it's gonna
fall off
get it get an achievement
so it's called atopa
okay so
now we're going to go off on a subject
called what do you want to call that in
english chimichanga
it don't go away
did you get a don't go away
did you pick up a don't go away when you
donated the money to asia alll
were you careful to to get a don't go
away from from powell when you made the
donation to the club club
did she also give you a
a don't go away did you get it don't did
you pick up but don't go away
okay got it it's a contract in a way we
guarantee
that you're gonna have prosperity why
you just donated money to the most
important project in the universe
okay so we give you a written guarantee
that's called a pangya
or chu misawa banga that's a
don't go away contract okay got it all
right because we're gonna spend now like
a couple hours on don't go away
contracts okay
okay
means
it's like when you take a loan bulenchen
means is similar to when you take a loan
they give you a contract and you sign it
okay
you when you take the money
you get the contract that don't go away
contract that don't go away means you
don't go away without paying back
okay
all right so you can have a don't go
away with good things and with bad
things
okay all right here we go we're gonna
dig
deeper into
don't go aways
okay it's a noun right all right
and that's gonna be pretty much the rest
of the chapter now uh
now
the guardian is gonna repeat
what the last 700 years that guys
said about
don't go away
don't go away what's the don't go away
look like well i'll tell you okay
denis
according to khan meaning daughter
meaning realm
okay those can be divided into three you
got don't go aways in the
desired realm you got don't go away in
the
form realm you got don't go aways in the
formless realm but he says for why
in the abhidharma system you can have
something outside the realms
and that's pure things
you know like nirvana or buddhahood this
he says you can get it don't go away
that's not in sansara it's outside the
sensor so let's call it four
three for the satsaric realms
and one that's outside of censor four
don't go with
whose idea
abhidharma
meaning some
some detailers some of the guys
all right so first you can divide it
into four times depending on where
that don't go away is residing
okay what's next
what's lumaten you guys know this gewa
it's not gewa it's not miguel
yeah karmically neutral okay and that's
a little tricky
a lot of these
instruments
which keep spiritual stuff on you
are karmically neutral themselves
so hey don't go away
a contract isn't good or bad i mean
there can be bad stuff in the contract
or there can be good stuff in the
contract but the paper is like you know
the instrument the vehicle for the
contract which is a
don't go away
is neutral he's like paper then you can
write something nasty on the paper or
you can write something nice on the
paper but the don't go away
is neutral and then it could be a bad
one it could be a good one okay
all right next verse
there's a mistake in the carving when
very important
it is not eliminated by tongan
yeah you can see emptiness directly
and it doesn't do anything to your
don't go away
okay
delicate question okay but by the way
the guardian is trying to impress on us
what's a don't go away what makes karma
stick to you
what makes karma stick to you you know
well it's don't go waste what's a don't
go away like well it's currently neutral
it could be in different realms
and
unfortunately you don't drop the dunk
always when you see
emptiness directly
but maybe you get rid of the bad karma
but keep the don't go away
okay question we're not sure yet
okay and gombe
uh
it is eliminated by the path of
habituation hundred dollars tell me why
it should be
100 don't forget what school we're in
don't forget what's cool we're in
and
what if i say a don't go away
can be eliminated
at the end of the path of habituation
why what happens there
lower school
lower school and you're suffering
more i want more precision for a hundred
dollars i need at least two words
lower school
bim okay i'm cutting it to fifty dollars
lower nirvana cut the flow
of pimple and
lower for twelve dollars
i forget the bet bimbo means you're a
material
body
and rigba means your mind gunship means
in in the lower school you you blink out
you just blink out
then you don't suffer anymore yay
then the debate by the higher schools is
not too complicated okay
what's nirvana according to you
oh you blink out
what your body blinks out your mind
blinks huh right what do we call you
then arhan where is our hut
nowhere
okay it's a very funny
that's an ancient debate where's the
iron
all right
so
probably your don't go aways are gonna
finish if your
body and mind
okay all right
uh thank you
don't forget we were having this trouble
of saying if the karmic seed changes
right oh sorry if it doesn't change it
can't give a result
and if it if it does change moment by
moment
it disappears in 1 65th of a second so
how can it transmit your how can there
be a chumisa
how can there be a what do we call it
american
no what what's the word we use how can
the don't go away
flow over time if it's
instant coming in and out of existence
moment by moment okay
then he says here
uh daichi misawa it's not the karmic
seed that creates the karmic result it's
the don't go away
the seed comes and goes
but the don't always stay
then when the seed disappears the don't
go away stays with you and then the
don't go away gives you the money later
after you give a donation
got it
the don't go away can stay
got it okay okay this is okay i can see
you're impressed with this idea
all right okay
if the don't go away could disappear
uh just because you reached a higher
path in the fight pass
or just because something's happened to
your karma in general
then you could hurt somebody and never
get a result
which breaks every law of karma and
everything the buddha ever said okay if
the don't go away
could be eliminated even by great
spiritual attainment
then
then you're saying you could do a bad
deed and get no result
not possible okay so the don't go away
has to stay
okay maybe it doesn't create anything
i'm sunni telling you look at all the
problems you're causing then he says so
he says other problems too and then
chonin says are you curious about what
the other problem was and we're like
yeah we were really wondering
and he says
problem number three law number three of
karma
yeah if you don't do it you're not gonna
get a problem okay if you don't steal
money you're never gonna lose money okay
karmic law number three if you don't do
it you don't get a result karmic law
number four if you do do it it's not
gonna just fade away
okay got it so the chimney is now our
principle
of uh when it wasn't don't
don't go away the don't go away is so
useful because we can still keep the
last two laws of karma
okay okay
all right here we go by the way i have a
titanic sneaking here you ready patchy
i worked so hard you know there's no
pictures of the titanic sinking
so i got this one for you guys
and
okay
by the way
if the titanic if you
if you had a credit card when you got on
the titanic and you used it a lot on the
titanic
and then it sank
how's your bangja
how's your credit card bill what's it
gonna look like
zero okay got it
you don't go away staying with the
titanic
okay that represents nirvana
that the discontinuation of your body
and mind okay that's the thinking of the
titan
okay it also takes your credit card
bills
okay nobody on the titanic got charged
for
the food and drink thing i wonder
probably not right
the company probably failed the next day
so anyway
i thought it was a cute example of
discontinuation of body and mind and
then all those pangas all those credit
card agreements went down the ship
then maybe nirvana is defined by
finally your escape your credit card
bills
why there's nobody in mind to pay them
got it
okay this is a cute photo in there
uh i thought we should take a vacation
to the sanskrit
for don't go away what's the sanskrit
for a
so it's four parts
[Music]
okay so please repeat ah
sorry nash
nasha
[Music]
means to be lost
or to fade away got it
very much
very much completely didn't fade away
[Music]
okay got it
so you can use the sunscreen
hey you got any don't go waste
i'm sorry you gotta i'll be pronouncious
he's like yeah i got some of the
panaches i hope i could keep the avi
pronounces of my donation to the gold
club and i hope i can lose the
abhiprenations when i reach nirvana of
all my credit card debts
all right
so learn the word okay not generally
nash as a root in sanskrit means to be
destroyed or to be lost it's probably
connected to not
okay all right
next verse
by the way it's a long chapter i'm sorry
okay but i know you guys are fascinated
uh
okay now the other guy says
well if you can lose your obvious
of the pronocious
it sounds like a jewish pastry
oh
you can get where is that nice baker is
it still there um what's
going on
yeah
no
you know that one goes in and out of
business like all the time no but it was
there for like a hundred years
okay anyway you can pick up some other
productions there
anyway
uh
the guy says
okay i understand that if the titanic
sinks all the credit card bills go but
what about life to life
do you lose your avi pronouncious when
you skip to a new life when you cross
the border nintendo
into a new reaper
do the abhi pranashas come with you do
that can't go always come with you or
not what do you guess
prop they do go away
they probably don't go away otherwise
there would be no karma in the next
level
okay here's the real answer
uh kamsuni chatsundam if you go from the
same rebirth to the same rebirth if you
go from human to human you keep your abi
pernicious
okay
or if you go from desire around to
desire realm you keep your upper
emotions chanting but i'm jeky there
might be some not keeping your abi
pronounces when you change to a
different realm because those devas are
not going to have the obvious suffering
that you should have had if you were
born in the human realm right
if you had gone from the human world to
the human realm you'd be having some
gross sufferings that devas don't have
so if you go from human to deva
something must have happened to some of
your avipanishas for for for trouble
because they don't have trouble
you got it
all right
now i mean when you go from a human
birth to a daddy birthday by birth
uh
in that birth you don't have
the the gross pain that you have in this
room nobody breaks their arm in the
diving room
it doesn't happen okay so maybe
something happens to your heavy
pronounces
if you go to a different realm from the
human world
all right
okay ready
i'm sorry
your karma might not go with you but
your
i'll avi pranasha will go with you how's
that
hey
your karma may not go with you but your
what did we call it your don't go away
we'll go with you how's that this is all
i'll be done okay i'm sorry
okay
by the way
the only reason why nicaragua would give
a lot of
wild abu dharma ideas is if he's gonna
destroy them at some point
i'm just i'm just telling you
all right next verse i'll say i'm sorry
next verse
now tonight
can mean
something you saw at the path of seeing
but it can also mean dershta adarshta
seen in this lie or seen in the future
now okay and that's what it means here
okay so as far as
are you gonna see it
uh as far as thursday durst up when you
do any kind of
but how should we say
any time you commit a karma in this life
your
won't go away is dershta in this life
you pick it up in this life okay
whatever karma you come in in this life
you pick up and don't go away for that
in this life
and that could apply to suction or sagma
in the abhidharma system good good karma
uh
impure karmas are pure chromos which is
a long subject okay
uh
lay down
also both types of chetana
and
chatana and
we studied a long time ago yesterday
[Music]
yeah yeah
intention and intended
okay so that division
he says uh whether
you commit a karma mentally or whether
you commit a karma
because of what you were thinking
both of them you still pick up a
don't go away okay whether it's mental
karma which is thinking karma which is
intention
or it's the action of body or speech
which was intended by them
you still pick up but don't go away okay
this is all details of don't go waste
this is cool
you get a separate don't go away every
time you make a karma
so you're basically collecting don't go
aways your whole life
okay your whole life your pockets
filling up with don't go away
every tiny thing you do you get a new
don't go away it's discreet okay it says
here today
it arises discreetly
this is really controversial after the
karma ripens they don't go away
stays with you
well what's it do
don't ask me he doesn't say okay but
according to abhidharma
the donke always stays with you
even if the karma is destroyed or it
ripens
and it finishes
even if the seed finishes the don't go
away stays with you somehow so we must
be collecting zillions of don't go with
what do they do if they don't hold the
karma anymore
it's kind of like an
empty pocket after you spend all your
money
i guess you could still have the pocket
ready
all right uh
now the avida guy says nagorjana
you forgot to tell them how to get rid
of your donko waist
and the guys are like oh yeah let's talk
about that okay so here's how to get rid
of your donko waste extra dongle waist
all right danny david power down she was
giving a gap again the second part here
is easy if you shiwa you lose your dog
always
yeah if you die
you lose some don't go waste
it doesn't seem to make sense because
you should be able to carry it into your
neckline
means serious heavy
heavy
graduating
karmic result
this refers to uh
street
uh stream enter
once returner non-returner and arhat
these are called the force the four
fruits
when the fruit is big
heavy good karma heavy spiritual
realizations
yeah i could cancel your dunk always
and and i can i i don't know but i'm
imagining
joy lumps
the mastery level of joyron
you can't go to uh
you can't go to lower realm anymore so
they must have destroyed your
donkey waist it must have damaged some
of your donko waste but then he just
said they can only be lost when you
become an artist i don't know
okay
you could have
enlightened don't go ways and you can
have some sorry
sons sorry don't go away
okay this everyone in the room is going
to sleep let's see if we can go on uh
i like this picture okay apache uh
i built my llama's house it took me oh
wait there's one more picture
yeah i
i built my llamas house
i i
i paid for it and i built it
and uh
and it and no one came to help me i mean
one guy helped me for a day or something
so i was i was up on this height it's
two stories high i was up in the third
story on the ladder
and i'll never forget it it was winter
dead of winter i'm up on the ladder
painting the
house like this
and uh these people would come i'm going
old men and they'd say hey mike i'm like
what
i got to go to the store
and i'm like i'm painting the house that
no one's helping me paint
and he said but i'm going to start anita
ryan you know i was the chibitbag
i was the public horse
of the whole community so anyway why am
i talking about that if you get high
enough you leave the toolbox at the
bottom if if you're working on the third
story you always forget some tool
and then you have to climb down this
very dangerous ladder two stories and uh
get the screwdriver and go back up and
then you forgot the paint you know
and you're by yourself and anyway
what i'm saying is if you get high
enough you can leave some of your
don't go away
behind
okay i don't know why that image came in
my mind
all right uh
let's go to the next verse
so so we start saying uh
we start thinking
well then this whole don't go away thing
is starting to sound a little
uncomfortable you know this this feels
like a really a lower idea
that
once you commit a karma it can't just go
away it starts to feel uncomfortable
right this whole idea of a don't go away
you know
it sounds weird you know then suddenly
the godzilla shifts gears
he says following verse
hey don't think don't go is our stupid
idea there's a real don't go away
as he seems to shift gears here he's
like
look i know you guys now you don't have
much respect for don't go waste but
there is a real don't go away
let me tell you about the real don't go
away okay and then he starts to describe
it
don't think that just because something
is empty it's gonna destroy the don't go
away
don't go do exist
and they are empty
but that doesn't mean they don't
keep your seed
okay
don't think that don't go aways
can't
hold your karma with you
for lifetimes
uh just because they are empty
okay that's a misunderstanding empty
when i say a don't go away is empty
i don't mean it doesn't work
because you guys keep thinking that
every time i say empty you guys think it
doesn't matter anymore
but when i say empty i mean it does
matter
okay don't go ways are empty therefore
you better learn about them and respect
them because it means they were
it doesn't mean they don't work okay so
that's the first thing the garcia has to
say
dominique
means
this this
what do we say bam negan chip but this
when you cut off the floor or something
anyway
let's say cut off
yeah that's certainly a mistake
by the way i missed the 10 gear version
and the challenging level version so i
could
detect problems
you i have the channel version you have
the
10 year version and the reason i did
that so i could detect any problems
so anyway uh tomba need on
so don't think that's because it's empty
your
your don't go away is just gonna
disappear chipper
uh truncate right we had the two
extremes thinking things are
unchanging and thinking things just stop
okay
third thing
korwa us
you better figure out
this don't go away thing says nagarjuna
first of all because the buddha said it
and secondly because it is the king of
samsara
it runs sansar
don't go away run censor
okay they are the bus drivers for
sansara
okay the don't go aways in your karmic
pocket
are the bus driver of your samsara okay
so you got them better figured out
because they keep your karmas with you
okay so you better figure it out so he
says this is not bs
this is real the buddha talked about it
we have to figure it out and because
they are running your suffering
last thing
don't think they are unchanging okay
that's not
correct don't think
that a karma stored over time would have
to be unchanging that's also a
misperception the buddha did say
karma can be stored over time and come
back to you
that doesn't mean the karma is
unchanging it just means it's
replicating or something like that
so what he's saying is
i've made a lot of fun
of the abhidharma guys
in a bunch of verses here but actually
they're pretty cool
this idea that you could
that comment don't go away
that's that's for real that's for real
okay he says
i just brought it up because you guys
think
if it's empty a don't go away can't wear
but i want to tell you if it's empty
that's the proof that it can work and
karma will stay with you so you better
watch your karma this don't go away
stuff is for real
why buddhist buddhism
that's nigari
and
[Music]
it seems like a long class but it's okay
right all right here we go
[Music]
that goes into why a don't go away
should work
the guardian who goes into why i don't
go away should work and he says
don't go
don't go away as work because you cannot
do karma
don't go away to work
because you cannot do karma
meaning
which exists
from its own side
so he's he's kicking you know he's now
he's like yay finally i confused you
okay here i'll say it again
don't always work
because karma you cannot do karma don't
go always work because you cannot do
karma okay
data action made their chair why
because karma doesn't have any nature of
its own okay it's coming from muslim
country
and because you cannot do karma
it's gonna stay with you without going
away
because you cannot do karma
it's gonna stay with you and cannot just
go away
because you cannot do kramer you do get
don't go waste
got it
because you cannot do karma
you do get those donkeys
if that sounds like karma and yogurt
okay
uh don't always keep karma on your on on
christina whoever christine is
yeah it's like a glue this is a very
i'll be normal idea
by the way if you want to get if you
really want to ask questions
what keeps the glue on you
right then they abhidharma says tope
topa
you got to have a glue for the glue
then they say then the other guy says
well do you have a toffee top it over do
you have glue for the glue for the glue
and they say nope you didn't set the
glue for the grill
so don't worry you don't need glue for
your glue you don't need glue for your
glue glue but you do need glue
all right
i like this next picture it's called the
rules
why stuff works
and
the rules i like to say the rules hold
true because they don't exist
okay you got to follow the rules of
karma
because they don't exist meaning
even the laws of karma are coming from
you
well then they should be adjustable
if the laws of karma
are coming from me
then i should be able to do a good deed
and get a bad result
you know under weird circumstances if
it's coming from me
then i should be able to mess with the
laws of karma
and that's a that's a fallacy okay the
fact that something's coming from you
doesn't mean you could change it
that there's not patterns
that there's not
inevitable patterns
the fact that something's coming from
you
is not a proof
that there are not inevitable patterns
in life
and that if you hurt someone you're
gonna get hurt okay are you creating
that law yes can you change that law no
well if it's coming from me i could
change it might count not necessarily
okay we'll talk about it
okay uh it's a tough class uh listen to
it a bunch of times we're not done with
our examination karma we got one more
class to go okay see you next one
you